Guide to the Denise Levertov Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 2. Manuscripts
  - b. Prose
    - The Legend of the Good Bishop Coholmleywynnydsy, n.d., TMs w/ drawings, 6 pp. (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Le Pont Lever, n.d., AMs, 4 pp. (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Letter to Liturgy Committee on Inclusive Language, 1988 Jan. 10, TMs, 11 pp. (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Light up the Cave: Poetry and Revolution, 1981, TMs, 1 p. (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Light up the Cave: Speech for Boston Common, 1979 Sept. 15, Ams, Tms, 9 pp. (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - from Light up the Cave, 1981, 2 AMs, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Literature of Conscience. Bumbershoot, 1988, AMs, facsim., 28 pp. (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - A Little Horror, c. 1983-184, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 22, Folder 35)
    - Memorial Day 1988, 1988, AMs, 10 pp; TMs and photocopies of poetry 26 pp. (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - Memories of Vietnam, n.d., TMs, 5 pp; 2 copies (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - Memories of Vietnam, n.d., AMs, 9 pp. (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - "Mental Landscape": List of Important Readings, n.d., facsim, 4 pp. (Box 22, Folder 39)
    - "Minority of One", 1982 June 15, facsim, 1 p. (Box 22, Folder 40)
    - A Minor Role (essay about DL's father), n.d. (c. 1980) (Box 22, Folder 41)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1960, 5 AMs, 8 pp. (Box 22, Folder 42)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1960, 4 AMs, 18 pp. (Box 22, Folder 43)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1960, 5 AMs, 5 pp. (Box 22, Folder 44)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1960, 4 AMs, 4 pp. (Box 22, Folder 45)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1960, 3 AMs, 10 pp. (Box 22, Folder 46)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1960, 5 AMs, 7 pp. (Box 22, Folder 47)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1960?, 5 AMs, 7 pp. (Box 22, Folder 48)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1960, 3 AMs, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 22, Folder 49)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1964 - 1966, 11 AMs, 2 TMs, 27 pp. (Box 22, Folder 50)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1966, 2 AMs, 8 TMs, 19 pp. (Box 22, Folder 51)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1966, 3 TMs, 3 pp. (Box 22, Folder 52)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1967, 2 AMs, 2 pp. (Box 22, Folder 53)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1967 - 1969, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 22, Folder 54)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1960s, 4 AMs, 5 pp. (Box 22, Folder 55)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1969 - 1971, 4 AMs, 4 pp. (Box 22, Folder 56)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1970, 8 AMs, 27 pp. (Box 22, Folder 57)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1971, TMs, AMs, 5 pp. (Box 22, Folder 58)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1972, AMs, 14 pp. (Box 22, Folder 59)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1973 - 1974, AMs, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 22, Folder 60)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1975 - 1982, 12 AMs, 23 pp. (Box 22, Folder 61)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1980 - 1981, 6 AMs, 24 pp. (Box 22, Folder 62)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1980 - 1981, 2 AMs, TMs, 8 pp. (Box 22, Folder 63)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1980 - 1981, 9 AMs, 9 pp. (Box 22, Folder 64)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1981, 3 AMs, 12 pp. (Box 22, Folder 65)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1982, 2 AMs, 3 pp. (Box 22, Folder 66)
    - miscellaneous (essays, political prose, teaching), c. 1982, 6 AMs, 19 pp. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - miscellaneous (essays, speeeches), c. 1982 - 1983, 5 AMs, TMs, 42 pp. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1983, 7 AMs, TMs, 38 pp. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - miscellaneous, c. 1984 - 1988, 8 AMs, TMs, 18 pp. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - miscellaneous, n.d., 3 AMs, 9 pp. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - miscellaneous, n.d., 2 AMs, 5 pp. (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - miscellaneous, n.d., 9 pp. (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - miscellaneous fragments, c. 1980 - 1982, 2 AMs, 2 pp. (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - miscellaneous fragments, n.d. [c. 1984 - 1987], 11 AMs, 19 pp. (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - miscellaneous fragments, n.d. [c. 1984 - 1987], 7 AMs, 12 pp. (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Prose: Mutability, n.d., TMs, 3 pp. (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - "My intro. to lit. was largely oral", n.d., AMs, 3 pp. (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - The Natural Guard. New Age, n.d., 4 pp. (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - "A Necessary Poetry" (With notes on Zukovsky), 1960, TMs, AMs, 10 pp. (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Notebook Pages, c. 1965, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - A Note on Larry Eigner's Poems, 1959 June, AMs, 3 TMs, 22 pp. (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - A Note on the Theme, "The Sacred and the Secular", n.d., AMs, 3 pp. (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - A Note (on the Work of the Imagination), c. 1960 - 1963, AMs, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Notes for an anthology, n.d., AMs, facsim, 2 pp. (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Notes for a poetry reading, c. 1956, AMs,5 pp. (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Notes for a reading, n.d., AMs, 3 pp. (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Notes for Bloy piece, c. 1984, 3 AMs, 45 pp. (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Notes for Muhlenberg Reading, c. 1961, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Notes for political prose, c. 1973, AMs, 2 pp.AMs, 1 p. and newsclippings (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Notes for readings, 1968 - 1970, 8 AMs, 14 pp. (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Notes on Discovery, n.d., 2 AMs, 13 pp. (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - On Artists' Roots ina Landscape [1 of 4], n.d., AMs, TMS facsim, 16 pp. (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - On Artists' Roots ina Landscape [2 of 4], n.d., AMs, 26 pp. (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - On Artists' Roots ina Landscape [3 of 4], n.d., TMs with holographic notes, 13 pp. (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - On Artists' Roots ina Landscape [4 of 4], n.d., TMs, 13 pp. (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - On Being a Poet ["To be a poet is not a career but a calling....", n.d., TMs w/ holographic notes, 19 pp. (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - On Being a Poet, n.d., AMs, 9 pp. (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - On Chekhov, n.d., TMs, 4 pp. (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - On City Hall Park, Birmingham, Alabama, c. 1963, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - On Civil Disobedience, n.d., facsim, 1 p. (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - On Copper Canyon Press, n.d. [1996], TMs, 3 pp. (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - On Duncan, Robert, c. 1955-1960, 5 AMs, 7 pp (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - On Duncan, Robert, c. 1960, AMs, 4 pp. (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - On economic embargos, 1990s, AMs, 4 pp. (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - On El Salvador, c. 1983 - 1984, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - On El Salvador, 1984 May, AMs, 2 TMs, 18 pp. (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - "On Engaged Art", n.d., facsim, 3 pp. (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - On Form, c. 1964 - 1966, AMs, 2 TMs, 25 pp. (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - "On friends and lovers", c. 1975, facsim, AMs 8 pp. (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - On Hall, Richard, Alice Walker, Robert Dana, Maureen McCabe, c. 1973 - 1975, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 23, Folder 45)
    - On H.D., n.d., AMs, 4 pp. (Box 23, Folder 46)
    - On H.D., n.d., AMs, 7 pp. (Box 23, Folder 47)
    - On Hikmet, Nazim: Human Landscapes, n.d. (c. 1981?), AMs, TMs, 12 pp. (Box 23, Folder 48)
    - On Hochman, Sandra and Joanne de Longchamps, c. 1960 - 1963, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 23, Folder 49)
    - On Jacob, n.d., TMs [gragment] w/ holographic notes, 4 pp. (Box 23, Folder 50)
    - On Jimmy Santiago Baca's work, 1981 - 1986, TMs, AMs, 26 pp. + 1 copy (Box 23, Folder 51)
    - On John Daniel's poems, c. 1988, AMs, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 23, Folder 52)
    - On Lax, Robert: The Circus of the Sun, 1996, TMs, 2 pp.; TLS (Box 23, Folder 53)
    - On Meyers, Bert, c. 1980 - 1981, AMs, 7 pp. (Box 23, Folder 54)
    - On Miller, Vassar and Rosemary Tonks, c. 1964 - 1966, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 23, Folder 55)
    - On Modern English Poetry, c. 1964 - 1966, AMs, 11 pp. (Box 23, Folder 56)
    - On Modern Poetry, c. 1965, AMs, 17 pp. (Box 23, Folder 57)
    - On Opening a Space for Poetry, n.d., AMs, 2 pp. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - On Organic Form, c. 1964 - 1966, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - On Other Poets (including Brinnin, Harrison, Sloman), c. 1961-1965, 2 AMs, 3 TMs, 5 pp. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - On Paz, Octavio, c. 1960, AMs, 4 pp. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - On Poetics, c. 1960, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - On Poetics, c. 1980 - 1981, 3 AMs, TMs, 8 pp. (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - On Poetics, c. 1960s, TMs, 14 pp. (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - On Poetry, c. 1961-1965, 5 AMs, TMs (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - On Poetry, c. 1962, 2 AMs, TMs (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - On Poetry, c. 1964 - 1966, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - On Poets/Poetry, 1986, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - On Poets/Poetry, 1970s, 2 AMs, 6 pp. (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - On Prison Poetry, n.d., AMs, 9 pp. (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - On Redds, T.J., c. 1973, 4 TMs, 6 pp. (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - On Randlett, Mary, n.d., TMs, AMs, 25 pp. (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - On Return from Hanoi, c. 1972, AMs, 22 pp. (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - On Revision, c. 1955, AMs, 5 pp. (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - On Rexroth, Kenneth, c. 1981, AMs, 8 pp. (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - On Rukeyser, M.'s translations of Octavio Paz, c. 1965, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - On Sources of Poetry, n.d., AMs, 17 pp. (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - On the Art of Prayer, c, 1990, TMs, 2 pp. (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - On the Edge of Darkness; What is Political Poetry? from Light Up the Cave, 1981, AMs, TMs, 22 pp. (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - "On the evening of January 29, 1970", n.d. (a970s), TMs, 3 pp. (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - On the Need for New Terms, 1986, facsim, 3 pp. (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - On the poetry of nature, n.d., AMs, 6 pp. (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - On the prose poem, 1953, AMs, 5 pp. (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - On the prose poem,. 1987, TMs, 1 p. (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - On the Relation between information and action, n.d., TMs, 4 pp. (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - on the social function of poetry, n.d., AMs, 5 pp. (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - On the social role of a poet, 1960s, AMs, 4 pp. (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - On Vietnam, c. 1975, AMs, 18 pp. (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - On War, n.d. (c. 1980s), AMs, 5 pp. (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - On Wieners, John: Ace of Pentacles, c. 1964, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - On Williams?, c. 1973 - 1974, AMs, 5 pp. + photocopies of poems (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - "On Williams' Triadic Line; or how to dance on variable feet" [galley proof for Ironwood. ==24], c. 1984, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - "On Williams' Triadic Line; or how to dance on variable feet", c. 1984, 10 pp. facsim, 2 copies. (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - "On Williams' Triadic Line; or how to dance on variable feet", c. 1984, 3 AMs, 29 pp. (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - On Williams, William Carlos, n.d., galley, 1 p. (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - An Open Letter to My Fellow Faculty Members, 1969 May 15, 2 TMs, 4 pp. (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - outline and short story, c. 1950?, AMs, 9 pp. (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - Pax Christi lecture, n.d., AMs, 11 pp. (Box 24, Folder 41)
    - 1987 Peace pentecost, 1987, AMs, TMs, 15 pp. (Box 24, Folder 42)
    - Personal statement for Radcliffe Scholar, c. 1963 - 1964, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 24, Folder 43)
    - Personal statement (the Paterson Society), 1961 Jan, TMs, 1 p. (Box 24, Folder 44)
    - "Pilgrimage"; Poetry Calendar, n.d., 2 pp. (Box 24, Folder 45)
    - The Poem as Counterforce: Responsibilities and Possibilities, c. 1964 - 1966, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 24, Folder 46)
    - "Poetics (Viva Voce to Gerardo Diego)", c. 1965, AMs, 1 p. (Box 24, Folder 47)
    - The Poet in the World [1 of 2], 1973, AMs, 3 TMs, 20 pp. (Box 24, Folder 48)
    - The Poet in the World [2 of 2], 1973, 4 AMs, TMs, 25 pp. (Box 24, Folder 49)
    - Poets of the Given Ground (review for The Nation of Paul Blackburn, Gil Sorrentino, Le Roi Jones, and Robert Lax), 1961 Oct. 14, TMs, 5 pp; clipping, 2 pp. (Box 24, Folder 50)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Austin, Mary, The American Rhythm [1923], n.d., facsim, 15 pp. (Box 24, Folder 51)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Brecht, Bertolt ["Brecht on Theater"], n.d., TMs, 6 pp. (Box 24, Folder 52)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Carlyle, Thomas: Heroes, Hero Worship and the Heroic, n.d., facsim, 5 pp. [fragments] (Box 24, Folder 53)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Crane, Hart, n.d., facsim, 28 pp. 2 copies (Box 24, Folder 54)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Eliot, T.S., n.d., mimeograph, 1 p. (Box 24, Folder 55)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Emerson, Ralph Waldo, n.d., facsim, 21 pp. (Box 24, Folder 56)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Frost, Robert, n.d., facsim, 9 pp. (Box 24, Folder 57)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Garcia Lorca, Federico, n.d., facsim, 7 pp. (Box 24, Folder 58)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Ginsberg, Allan ("To Eberhart from Ginsberg" Penmaen Press, 1976), 1976 (Box 24, Folder 59)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Hardy, Thomas, n.d., mimeograph, 2 pp. (Box 24, Folder 60)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Hazlitt, William, n.d., facsim, 2 pp. (Box 24, Folder 61)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Hopkins, Gerard Manley, n.d., facsim, 26 pp. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Poets on Poetry -- "Interweavings: Reflections on the Role of Dream in the Making of Poems", n.d., facsim, 9 pp. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Poets on Poetry -- James, Henry, n.d., facsim, 4 pp. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Jonson, Ben, n.d., facsim, 4 pp. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Keats, John, n.d., mimeograph, 5 pp. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Poets on Poetry -- O'Hara, Frank, n.d., facsim, 7 pp. (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Olson, Charles, n.d., facsim, 6 pp. (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Poets on Poetry -- "On the Need for New Terms", n.d., facsim, 3 pp. (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Pasternak, Boris, n.d., facsim, AMs, 22 pp. (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Pavese, Cesare, n.d., facsim, 11 pp. (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Pound, Ezra, n.d., AMs, facsim, 30 pp. (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Rilke, Rainer Maria, n.d., TMs, facsim, 80 pp; 2 copies (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Roethke, Theodore, n.d., TMs, facsim, 18 pp; 2 copies (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Rukeyser, Muriel, n.d., TMs, facsim, 52 pp; 2 copies (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Shelley, Percy Bysshe, n.d., facsim., 16 pp. (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Sidney, Sir Phillip, n.d., facsim., 24 pp. (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Sitwell, Edith, n.d., facsim., 6 pp. (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Poets on Poetry -- an introduction to Snyder, Gary, n.d., AMs, 1 p. (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Poets on Poetry -- "Some Notes on Organic Form", n.d., facsim, 4 pp. (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Stevens, Wallace, n.d., facsim, TMs, AMs, 39 pp. (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Supervielle, Jules, n.d., facsim, TMs, 10 pp. (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Poets on Poetry -- "Technique and Tune-up", n.d., facsim, 4 pp. (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Vonkleist, Heinrich, n.d., facsim, 4 pp. (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Williams, William Carlos, n.d., facsim, TMs, 70 pp. (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Poets on Poetry -- Zukovsky, Louis, n.d., facsim, 2 pp. (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Poets on Poetry -- notes, n.d., AMs, 8 pp. (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - "The Poet in the World": footnote, 1967, AMs, 1 p. (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Poetry and Our Lives, n.d., TMs, 1 p. (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Poetry and Peace: "Some Broader Dimensions" ["Poetic Vision and the Hope for Peace"], 1989, TMs, AMs, 29 pp. (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Points in Proust, n.d., AMs, 7 pp. (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Political Notes, c. 1970, 5 AMs, 12 pp. (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Political Prose, c. 1980 - 1981, 8 AMs, TMs, 32 pp. (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - Political Prose, c. 1980 - 1981, 2 AMs, 14 pp. (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Political Prose on Vietnam, c. 1973, 4 TMs, 15 pp. (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - Political Prose (re nuclear arms, Seabrook), c. 1977 - 1980, 3 AMs, TMs, 17 pp. (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - Political Prose ("What do I want to happen?..."), 1977, 2 TMs, 2 pp. (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Political Speech, n.d., AMs, 24 pp. (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - Political Speeches, c. 1967 - 1968, 5 TMs, 8 pp. (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Political Writing, c. 1986, AMs, 2 pp; TLs (Box 25, Folder 39)
    - "principles" (as editor of The Nation), c. 1964, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 25, Folder 40)
    - A Proposal from a Group of Parents to the Administrators of the American School, c. 1956, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 25, Folder 41)
    - Preamble, 1995, TMs, 27 pp facsim; 3 copies (Box 25, Folder 42)
    - Psalm 8, n.d., AMs, 52 pp. (Box 25, Folder 43)
    - Reading the Gospel of St. John, n.d., TMs, 45 pp. (Box 25, Folder 44)
    - The Remedy, n.d., TMs, 6 pp. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Resolution for the 1981 American Writers Congress, 1981, AMs, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Response to Question of Role of Art in Society, n.d. (c. 1960?), TLs, 2 AMs, 26 pp. (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Rilke as a Poet's Mentor, 1981, TMs, AMs, 1 p. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Role of the Poet, n.d., TMs w/ holographic notes, 6 pp. (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Russell Edson, c. 1960 - 1963, AMs, 3 pp. (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - "Sacred and Secular", n.d., TMsS, 2 pp. (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Sermon, Peace Pentecost (St. Paul's Cathedral, Boston), 1988, 3 pp. (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Short Story, n.d., AMs, 8 pp. (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - A Slow Violence, n.d., TMs, 2 pp. (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - "Some Affinities of Content", 1991, 46 pp. (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Some Duncan Letters -- A Memoir and a Critical Tribute, n.d., TMs--facsim., 16 pp. (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - "Some Duncan Letters -- A Memoir and a Critical Tribute: Afterword", 1991, 2 pp. (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Some Hasty Answers to Weighty Questions, c. 1988, TMs, 6 pp. (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - "Some notes on organic form" from Poet in the World, n.d., AMs, 2 TMs, 10 pp. (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Some notes on Robert Duncan's poems, 1960 - 1966, AMs, 2 TMs, 13 pp. (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - "Some things I know", n.d., AMs, 10 pp. (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - "Solzhenitsyn Reconsidered" The Real Paper, (1974 Feb 20), p. 1., 1974 Feb. 20 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - "A South Wind," Notes in the Margins (1993 Winter), p. 7., 1993 Winter (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - speech introducing Robert Duncan, Gilbert Sorrentino, Robert Lax, Jake Gilbert, D.L., and Sandra Hochman -- recommendation for [Guggenheim Fellowship], c. 1960, AMs, 17 pp. (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - speech on William Carlos Williams, c. 1981, AMs, 29 pp. (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - statement, c. 1960s, AMs, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - statement for the Radcliffe Institution, 1964, TMs, 1 p. (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - statement on poetry, n.d., TMs, 1 p. (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - summary of poems judged?, c. 1961-1965, AMs, 6 pp. (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Survival, Revelation, Quest, n.d., AMs, 4 pp. (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Taking the Language out for a Walk, c. 1972, TMs (facsim), 7 pp. (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Tesserae: "At Tawstock", n.d., AMs, 6 pp. (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Tesserae: "Cafe Royale", n.d., AMs, 18 pp. (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Tesserae: "Cordova", n.d., AMs (facsim), 11 pp. (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - Tesserae: "An Encounter -- and a Re-encounter", n.d., AMs, 11 pp. (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - Tesserae: "The Gardener", 1981, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - Tesserae: "Janus", n.d., AMs (facsim), 16 pp. (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - Tesserae: "Janus", n.d., AMs, 2 pp. (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - Tesserae: "Jinny", n.d., facsim, 2 pp. (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - Tesserae: "The Last of Childhood --for Jean, in this LIfe or the Next", n.d., AMs, 9 pp. (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - Tesserae: "The Last of Childhood --for Jean, in this LIfe or the Next", n.d., AMs, 4 pp. (Box 26, Folder 37)
    - Tesserae: "A Loss", 1981, facsim, 16 pp [2 copies] (Box 26, Folder 38)
    - Tesserae: "Lost Books", n.d., AMs, 6 pp. (Box 26, Folder 39)
    - Tesserae: "Meeting Miss Noar", n.d., AMs, 15 pp. (Box 26, Folder 40)
    - Tesserae: "Not Meeting Kokoschka", n.d., TMs, 4 pp. (Box 26, Folder 41)
    - Tesserae: "Oracles", n.d., AMs (facsim), 25 pp. [2 copies] (Box 26, Folder 42)
    - Tesserae: "A Pilgrimage", n.d., AMs (facsim), 7 pp. (Box 26, Folder 43)
    - Tesserae: "Pilgrimage", n.d., AMs, 7 pp. (Box 26, Folder 44)
    - Tesserae: "Some Hours in the late '70s", n.d., TMs, AMs, 57 pp. (Box 26, Folder 45)
    - Tesserae: "Some Hours in the late '70s", n.d., AMs (facsim), 27 pp. (Box 26, Folder 46)
    - Tesserae: "Some Things I know", n.d., facsim, 5 pp. (Box 26, Folder 47)
    - Tesserae: "What One Remembers", n.d., AMs, 6 pp. (Box 26, Folder 48)
    - Tesserae: "What One Remembers", n.d., AMs (facsim), 26 pp. [2 copies] (Box 26, Folder 49)
    - Tesserae: notes, n.d., AMs, 1 p. (Box 26, Folder 50)
    - Tesserae: page proofs [1 of 5], n.d., 32 pp. (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Tesserae: page proofs [2 of 5], n.d., 28 pp. (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Tesserae: page proofs [3 of 5], n.d., 22 pp. (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Tesserae: page proofs [4 of 5], n.d., 26 pp. (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Tesserae: page proofs [5 of 5], n.d., 52 pp. (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Prose: Tesserae and other related pieces [1 of 6], n.d., 43 pp. (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Prose: Tesserae and other related pieces [2 of 6], n.d., TMs, facsim, 42 pp. (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Prose: Tesserae and other related pieces [3 of 6], n.d., TMs, facsim, 32 pp. (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Prose: Tesserae and other related pieces [4 of 6], n.d., TMs, facsim, 43 pp. (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Prose: Tesserae and other related pieces [5 of 6], n.d., facsim, 30 pp. (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Prose: Tesserae and other related pieces [6 of 6], n.d., facsim, 37 pp. (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Textbook on Poetry Chapter II: Vocabulary, Etymology, Diction, n.d., TMs (facsim), 32 pp [2 copies] (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Textbook on Poetry Introductory Chapter Part II: Understanding the poem, n.d., TMs (facsim), 86 pp (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Textbook on Poetry: notes, clippings, correspondence, n.d., AMs, TMs (facsim), 61 pp. (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Textbook on Poetry: notes on Bathos, n.d., TMs, 2 pp. (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Text of speech at Rally, Boston Common, 1972 Nov. 18, TMs, 2 pp. (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - A Tree Telling of Orpheus: draft, n.d., Ams, 1 p. (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - The Tulips: Step by step analysis, c. 1965, TMs, 3 pp. (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - "To suppose that art can be politically and socially engaged....", n.d., TMs, 5 pp. (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Two Ancients, n.d., AMs, 2 pp. (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - unidentified book review, c. 1964 - 1966, AMs, 2 pp. (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - unidentified essays on art and society, c. 1964 - 1966, 2 AMs, 11 pp. (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - unidentified talk on poetry, c. 1965, TMs, 4 pp. (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - "very tall, very pale, a man of bone and mist..." (re Old Day, Gardener), n.d., AMs, 19 pp. (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Vietnam Notebook [1 of 3], 1972, AMs (facsim), 33 pp. (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Vietnam Notebook [2 of 3], 1972, AMs (facsim), 34 pp. (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Vietnam Notebook [32 of 3], 1972, AMs (facsim), 38 pp. (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - "Vocation", c. 1988, AMs, 6 pp. (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - Voice, n.d., AMs, 17 pp. (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - The War Years, 1948, TMs, TLs, 7 pp. (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - untitled insert, c. 1986, Ams, 2 pp. (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - untitled "Linda, Barry and Roger alighted at the little station joyfully...", n.d. (1940s?), AMs, 15 pp. (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - "What is a 'creative writing workshop al about'", n.d., AMs, 3 pp. (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - When I Pray; Compass, 1989, facsim, 4 pp. [4 copies] (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - Why Pax Christi?, n.d., TMs, 2 pp. (Box 27, Folder 35)
    - "Work that Enfaiths"; Cross Currents, 1990 Summer, 6 pp. (Box 27, Folder 36)
    - William Carlos Williams Essay (including notes), 1960s, TMs, AMs, 27 pp. (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - "Williams and Eliot", 1989, 2 TMS, 11 pp; AMs, 25 pp. (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - Work that Enfaiths: Notes for Wyschgorod response, 1990, AMs, 13 pp. (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - unfinished draft on Balaban, John, n.d., AMs, 1 p. (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - The Poet in the World: re Paul Goodman, c. 1960-1965, AMs, 9 pp. (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - El Salvador Requiem (1 of 8), 1980 - 1981 (Box 30, Folder 10)